<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on iowafloyd - an engineering blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on iowafloyd - an engineering blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 18:08:43 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project Management in Excel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/project-management-in-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 18:08:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/project-management-in-excel/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-project-management&#34;&gt;Why project management?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curriculum at Iowa State University taught me a lot (statics, mechanics, thermodynamics, procrastination&amp;hellip;), but it didn&amp;rsquo;t teach me anything about project management. Why is that? I&amp;rsquo;ve had to use some form of project management in my daily professional life since day one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m betting that project management is just one of those things that&amp;rsquo;s hard to put into a textbook. Because (at least in my experience) you only really learn project management when Plan A goes sideways. So you make Plan B&amp;hellip; half of which goes sideways. So you make&amp;hellip; You get it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/about/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hi-im-cameron&#34;&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Cameron&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer your first question, I was born and raised in the great state of &lt;strong&gt;Iowa, USA&lt;/strong&gt;, and my favorite band has always been &lt;strong&gt;Pink Floyd&lt;/strong&gt;. Hence the name, iowafloyd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;formal-education&#34;&gt;(Formal) Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in several industries since the late 20-aughts, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aerospace &amp;amp; Defense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commercial electronics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial rotating machinery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;informal-education&#34;&gt;(Informal) Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in these industries has been interesting, challenging, rewarding, and fun. When not doing that, I enjoy coding in my free time. I find coding to be so much more creative than engineering. You&amp;rsquo;re not limited to pesky things like physics. These are the main languages I&amp;rsquo;ve used:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-world&#34;&gt;Hello, World!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;strong&gt;iowafloyd&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have guessed from the moniker, I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;live in the United States state of Iowa, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;am very much influenced by the Prog Rock band Pink Floyd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowafloyd has been my online self ever since I created my first email address in the mid-90&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a Bachelor of Science degree in Mechanical Engineering, and mechanical engineering has been my profession since the late 20-aughts. In my spare time, however, and when the need arises in my day job, I code. My company&amp;rsquo;s IT team limits me to Excel and VBA, but outside of work I&amp;rsquo;ve used&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
